我们刚刚讨论了多个容器项目和 Docker 组成和
We just talked about multi container
projects and doing Docker compose and
Kubernetes，做一些很酷的事情
Kubernetes, doing some
really cool stuff like that,
协调容器。
coordinating containers together.
我们还会再去一次
And we're gonna go into one more section,
我们会把整个生态系统都抛在身后
we're gonna leave that
entire ecosystem behind.
我们将讨论一些叫做 OCI 容器的东西。
And we're going to talk about
something called OCI containers.
OCI 代表开放式容器计划。
And OCI stands for
open container initiative.
因此，这些将与非 Docker 容器相似。
So these are going to be
like non-Docker containers.
所以我们要做容器，但没有 Docker。
So we're going to do containers but
without Docker.
库兹我想向你证明 Linux 容器不仅仅是
Cuz I want to kind of prove the point to
you that Linux containers are not just
Docker， Docker 不仅仅是 Linux 容器。
Docker, Docker's not
just Linux containers.
然后我们就能拿到保监处的东西了
And so
we're gonna get into this OCI stuff.
所以我们要谈谈两种不同的技术。
So we're gonna talk about two different
technologies that are paired together.
一个叫 Buildah ，一个叫波德曼。
One's called Buildah, one's called Podman.
所以，让我们继续跳进 Buildah。
So let's go ahead and jump into Buildah.
首先，这些工具只在 Linux中工作。
So first of all,
these tools only work in Linux.
因此，我们将使用包含 Buildah 的 Docker 容器
So we are going to be using actually
a Docker container that contains Buildah
来完成所有这些我知道的容器内的容器
to make all this work, which I know
is containers within containers.
但这就是所有工作的方式。
But that's just kind
of how that all works.
因此，如果您正在使用 Windows 和 WSL ，那么一切都应该无缝地工作。
So if you're working with Windows and WSL,
everything should just work seamlessly.
你不应该用这个容器之类的东西。
You shouldn't have to use necessarily
the container or anything like that.
如果你在 Mac OS 上你得跟我一起跳进 Buildah 的集装箱里
If you're on Mac OS, you're gonna have to
jump into the Buildah container with me.
所以如果你想去查的话我就离开了
So I left a link there if
you wanna go check it out.
这就在 Docker Hub上。
That's just on Docker Hub.
因此， buildah 容器 ( buildah/buildah ) 具有 Buildah 和
So the Buildah container, which is
buildah/buildah, has both Buildah and
波德曼在其中你不需要两者
Podman in it, you don't need both.
你不需要两个不同的容器
You don't need two different containers.
所以在容器和容器周围
So a lot of the gravity
around containers and
这个容器的世界是围绕着 Docker 的，对吧 ?
the container world is
centered around Docker, right?
这是第一个市场。
That was the first to market.
它是那里的重心。
It's kind of the centre of gravity there.
而在努力的过程中，不一定要被锁定在一个弯管机上，因为我们没有
And in effort to not necessarily be
locked into one bender, because we don't
只需要一个云提供商，或者一个操作系统，或者仅仅是 iPhone 或
want just one cloud provider, or
one operating system, or just iPhone or
只有 Mac，才能有一个有竞争力的创意市场。
just Mac, it's a good idea to have
a competitive marketplace of ideas.
因此，当开放式容器计划开始实现的时候。
And so that's when the open container
initiative kind of came to fruition.
因此，它是 Linux Foundation 下的产品。
So it is a product underneath
the Linux Foundation.
所以它背后有很多支持。
So there's a lot of support behind it.
记住 Docker 是 OCI的一部分是一件好事。
And it's a good thing to keep in
mind that Docker is a part of OCI.
这不是 Docker 与 OCI 的对比，对吧 ?
So this is not like Docker versus OCI,
right?
他们都在竞争
They're both competing together and
互相帮助，这是一个非常合作的环境。
helping each other,
it's a very collaborative environment.
太棒了
So it's great.
另一件事是你可以用 Docker 和
And the other thing is that you can
build containers with Docker and
用波德曼和 Buildah来执行
execute them with Podman and Buildah.
反之亦然你可以用 Buildah 和 Podman
And visa versa, you can build
them with Buildah and Podman and
执行 Docker 。
execute them with Docker.
所以这些工具相互关联
So these tools interrelate and
它们在这种特殊的情况下是相容的
they're compatible with each
other in that particular way.
因此，它鼓励市场参与者的健康多样化。
So it encourages a healthy
diversity of players in the market.
大家都赢了
Everybody wins here.
所以 Buildah 和 Podman 不是唯一的项目
So Buildah and
Podman are not the only projects,
我最后再谈几个话题
I'll talk about a couple more at the end.
这些都是最有蒸汽的
These are just the two
that have the most steam,
那是我想在你面前做的
that are kind of rolling forward that
I wanted to get in front of you.
而且奇怪的是我们正在利用 Docker 和
And so it's kind of strange
that we're taking Docker and
我们要把它分成两个不同的产品， Buildah 和 Podman
we're splitting it into two different
products here, Buildah and Podman.
但实际上 Docker 实际上是分开的
But in reality,
Docker is actually split the same way,
你根本就没意识到
you just don't actually really realize it.
Docker， Docker ， Docker ，它是客户。
So Docker, there's actually Docker,
which is the client.
那是什么建筑之类的
Which does the building and
things like that.
有个不同的东西在叫 Dockerd的背景下运行
And there's a different thing running
in the background called Dockerd,
它代表 Docker 守护程序，实际上是执行代码的操作
which stands for Docker daemon, which is
actually what's executing the code for
或为您执行容器。
you, or executing the containers for you.
因此，当您说 docker 运行某些内容时，它会将它发送到 Docker 守护程序
And so when you say docker run something,
it sends that to the docker daemon in
通过 Docker 守护程序为您运行这些内容。
the background and it's running that
stuff for you via the Docker daemon.
所以即使你不知道那是在那里
So even though you didn't
know that that was there,
这就是正在发生的事情
that's actually what's happening.
这就是与 Buildah 和 Podman 分割的方式。
And that's kind of how this is
split with Buildah and Podman.
Buildah 准备为你建造容器
Buildah is going to build
the containers for you and
然后波德曼就会成为真正为你执行的人
then Podman is going to be the one
that's actually executing it for you.
波德曼 over Dockerd 的优势在于它实际上不是作为一个守护程序
The advantage of Podman over Dockerd is
it's actually not running as a daemon in
它的背景其实就是执行它
the background,
it's actually just executes it and
那样的人就会被淘汰
that kind of gets out of the way.
因此，让我们从 Buildah开始。
So let's get started with Buildah.
关于 Buildah 如何被命名的有趣之处
So the funny thing about
how Buildah was named,
它的名字叫 " 波士顿口音" 的建造者
it's named how you would say
builder with a Boston accent.
因为这个项目的核心保持者显然是
Because apparently one of the core
maintainers of this project was from
他一直叫 " buildah" 。
Boston and he always called a buildah.
我对这件事没有很好的印象因为我不是从波士顿来的
Which I'm not doing a very good impression
of it, because I'm not from Boston.
但我觉得这很有趣
But I thought that was very funny.
因此，您可以遵循指示信息下载和执行
So you can follow the instructions
to download and execute and
如果你想的话这些东西都在这里
all that kind of stuff
here if you want to.
我只是直接用它的容器
I'm just gonna use it
direct from the container,
也可以自由地跟我做同样的工作
feel free to do the same with me.
如果你要把它安装在我的 WSL 电脑里
If you are going to install it, which
I did do within my WSL computer here,
你很可能需要把它放在 registry.com上。
you will very likely need to
put here at this registry.com.
你可能需要把这个贴在里面
You will probably need to put this,
which I pasted in there.
我又要用这个集装箱了，所以
Again, I am going to be
using the container, so
我不会做这种事但你可能需要这个
I'm not going to do anything like that,
but you might need this.
你还得确保你有个叫 " runc" 的东西
And you're also gonna have to make
sure you have this thing called runc,
又是这个开放式容器倡议项目的另一个项目。
which is another project, again, from
this open container initiative project.
而 runc 只是说，嘿，拿着这个容器，做点什么，对吧 ?
And runc is just say, hey, take this
container and do something with it, right?
以某种方式执行该操作，即 runc 是什么。
Execute it in some fashion,
that's what runc is.
Runc underpins Buildah 和 Podman。
Runc underpins Buildah and Podman.
好吧我们走吧
All right, so let's go ahead and
运行 Buildah 或容器。
run Buildah, or the container.
所以我要在我的环境里做这个
So I'm gonna run this in my environment.
这将会运行 Buildah 容器
And this will run
the Buildah container and
它将安装在当前目录中，无论您在何处。
it will mount in your current directory,
wherever you are.
所以我要过来这里
So I'm gonna come over here to this.
让我们做更多的复杂， cd， oops，
Let's do the more-complicated, cd, oops,
../more-复杂化节点应用程序。
../more-complicated-node app.
这是我们所做的
This is something we did with,
太棒了太棒了
Yeah, this is great, perfect.
所以我们要做这个
So we'll do this one.
所以我要在那儿运行 Docker 命令
So I'm gonna run that
Docker command right there.
再次，如果您要通过 Docker 来执行此操作，请执行此操作。
Again, if you're gonna do this via Docker,
do it this way.
如果您不通过 Docker 来执行此操作，那么无需运行此操作。
If you're not gonna do it via Docker,
you don't need to run this.
这将会安装在此目录中，即源代码。
So this is going to mount in this
directory right there, source.
好了，现在我在一个容器里面，正在运行。
Okay, so now I'm inside of a container,
which is going to be running.
我们去看看我都不知道
Let's check, I don't even know.
etc/发出的信息。
etc/issue.
我很确定这是红帽
And I'm pretty sure that this is Red Hat.
所以，让我们一起去吧，我认为这是 Red Hat Linux。
So let's go with that,
I think this is Red Hat Linux.
好了现在我可以进入 Buildah了
Okay, and so now I have access to Buildah.
版本，你去吧
Version, there you go.
很酷吧
Cool?
这是一个写在 Go的工具，以防你好奇。
It's a tool written in Go,
in case you were curious.